Guide to the Alison Lurie papers, [ca. 1960-2013]
Lurie, Alison papers, [ca. 1960-2013]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alison Lurie papers, [ca. 1960-2013]
14-12-2572
Alison Lurie
5 cubic feet.
Notes, drafts, proofs, manuscript, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Notes, drafts, and printer's proofs of books by Lurie including Love and Friendship, Imaginary Friends, Real People, Foreign Affairs, The War Between the Tates, The Truth About Lorin Jones, Women and Ghosts, and The Last Resort; manuscript of a short story; and correspondence. Correspondents include Saul Bellow, Robert Creeley, Sue Kaufman, David Garnett, Edward Gorey, Christopher Isherwood, Olivia Manning, Arthur Mizener, Anthony and Violet Powell, Philip Roth, Jean Stafford, and Edmund Wilson. Also, a draft of the first chapter of Real People, annotated by Philip Roth.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Alison Lurie was born in 1926 and is the author of Love and Friendship (1962), Imaginary Friends (1967), The War Between the Tates, Real People (1969), Only Children (1979), Language of Clothes (1981), and other novels. Professor emerita of English at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Notes, drafts, and printer's proofs of books by Lurie including Love and Friendship, Imaginary Friends, Real People, Foreign Affairs, The War Between the Tates, The Truth About Lorin Jones, Women and Ghosts, and The Last Resort; manuscript of a short story; and correspondence. Correspondents include Saul Bellow, Robert Creeley, Sue Kaufman, David Garnett, Edward Gorey, Christopher Isherwood, Olivia Manning, Arthur Mizener, Anthony and Violet Powell, Philip Roth, Jean Stafford, and Edmund Wilson. Also, a draft of the first chapter of Real People, annotated by Philip Roth.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lurie, Alison.; Kaufman, Sue.; Garnett, David, 1892-; Isherwood, Christoper, |d 1904-; Manning, Olivia.; Mizener, Arthur.; Stafford, Jean, 1915-; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972.; Lurie, Alison.--Love and Friendship.; Lurie, Alison.--Imaginary Friends.; Lurie, Alison.--Real People.; Lurie, Alison.--Foreign Affairs.; Lurie, Alison.--War Between the Tates.; Lurie, Alison.--Truth About Lorin Jones.; Lurie, Alison.--Women and Ghosts.
Occupations:
Women authors.; Authors.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 15: Philip Roth letters and annotations, require permission of Mr. Roth during his lifetime.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Books
Real People
Box 1
Love and Friendship
Box 1
Ro of Varna
Box 2
Imaginary Friends
Box 2
V. R. Lang - A Memoir
Box 2
Foreign Affairs
Boxes 3, 4
The Truth About Lorin Jones
Boxes 4-6, 8
The War Between the Tates
Box 4
Counting Sheep
Box 4
Women and Ghosts
Box 7
The Last Resort
Boxes 9, 10, 11
The Nowhere City
Box 11
Series II. Other Works
Boxes 1, 2, 12, 14, 15
Series III. Correspondence
Box 2, 14, 15
Series IV. Miscellaneous
Boxes 2, 13, 14, Mapcase Folder 1
Series V. Photographs
Box 14
Series VI. Cornell Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Books
  - Real People
    - Real People (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Real People (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Real People - Final Revisions (1) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Real People - Final Revisions (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Real People - Final Version (1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Real People - Final Version (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Real People - ? Version (1) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Real People - ? Version (2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Real People - Text setting copy (1), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Real People - Text setting copy (2), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Real People - Printer's proof, 6 Jan 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Real People - Printer's proof, 19 Feb 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Real People - Printer's proof - Author's set (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Real People - Plate proofs (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Love and Friendship
    - Love and Friendship - Notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Love and Friendship - Draft (1) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Love and Friendship - Draft (2) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Love and Friendship - Draft (3) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Love and Friendship - Draft (4) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Love and Friendship - Draft (5) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Love and Friendship - Final version used by printer (1), 28 Sep 1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Love and Friendship - Final version used by printer (2), 28 Sep 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Love and Friendship - Final version used by printer (3), 28 Sep 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Love and Friendship - Final version used by printer (4), 28 Sep 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Love and Friendship - Printer's proof (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Love and Friendship - reviews and letters, 1961-62 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Love and Friendship - British edition, 1962-67 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Love and Friendship - US edition, 1961-69 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Ro of Varna
    - Ro of Varna - Notes for revision (used), 1966, also cut material, preliminary notes, theory, etc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ro of Varna (1) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ro of Varna (2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ro of Varna (3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ro of Varna (4) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ro of Varna - First draft (1) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ro of Varna - First draft (2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ro of Varna - First draft (3) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ro of Varna - First draft (4) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ro of Varna - Second draft - incomplete (1) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ro of Varna - Second draft - incomplete (2) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ro of Varna - Second draft - incomplete (3) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ro of Varna - Third draft (1) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Ro of Varna - Third draft (2) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Ro of Varna - Third draft (3) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ro of Varna - Third draft (4) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Ro of Varna - Imaginary Friends (1) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Ro of Varna - Imaginary Friends (2) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Ro of Varna - Imaginary Friends (3) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Ro of Varna - Imaginary Friends (4) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Ro of Varna - US edition, 1966-67 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ro of Varna - US edition: reviews, 1967-68 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ro of Varna - British edition: letters and reviews, 1967-78 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Ro of Varna - British edition, 1966-67 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Imaginary Friends
    - Imaginary Friends (1) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Imaginary Friends (2) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Imaginary Friends - Letters, 1967-02-1968-06 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Book cover, undated invitation to Reading for Kennedy
  - V. R. Lang - A Memoir
    - V. R. Lang - A Memoir, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - V.R. Lang - 1975 ed., 1963-1964, 1975-1978, 1990, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      The New Review - Vol 2 No 15; photo of "Violet in Europe on her honeymoon"
    - V.R. Lang - Letters about Memoir, 1954-1961 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Foreign Affairs
    - Foreign Affairs - Plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Affairs - People (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Affairs - first draft (story) - rejected passages, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Affairs - chapter 9 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Affairs - chapter 9 - notes, etc. used (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Affairs - revisions - add in, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Affairs - used, cut (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 1-1 thru 2-14 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 2-15 thru 3-14 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 3-15 thru 4-29 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 4-30 thru 6-14 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 6-15 thru 8-14 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 8-15 thru 10-14 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Foreign Affairs - pp. 10-15 thru 12-29 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Foreign Affairs: London - Letters, 1985-1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Affairs: London - Reviews, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Affairs - London, 1984-1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, planning of celebration of publication
    - Foreign Affairs: US Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Foreign Affairs: US Letters, 1984-1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Foreign Affairs - US, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Book cover, congratulations of Pulitzer Prize achievement
    - Foreign Reviews, 1987-1990 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Itinerary for Paris trip, reviews for her other works (Foreign Affairs, Love and Friendship, Imaginary Friends, The Truth About Lorin Jones)
    - Foreign Reviews, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Articles about Foreign Affairs and The Truth About Lorin Jones
    - Feeling of Truth in Alison Lurie's Fiction: With Special Reference to Love and Friendship and Foreign Affairs, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - The Truth About Lorin Jones
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (1), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (2), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (3), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (4), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 1-1 thru 3-14 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 3-15 thru 5-14 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 5-15 thru 7-14 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 7-15 thru 9-14 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 9-15 thru 11-14 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 11-15 thru 13-14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - pp. 13-15 thru 16-22 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (5), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (6), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (7), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (8), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (9), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (10), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (11) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (12) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (13) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (14) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (15) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (16) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (17) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (18) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (19) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (20) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (21) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (22) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (23) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (24) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (25) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (26) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (27) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (28) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (29) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (30) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (31) (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (32) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (33) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (34) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (35) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (36) (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (37) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - early versions and notes (38) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - The Truth About Loren Jones - full manuscript, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Loren Jones - London, Reviews + Letters, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - The War Between the Tates
    - The War Between the Tates - outline and notes (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The War Between the Tates - lists of changes, Dec 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 1-1 thru 2-14 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 2-15 thru 3-14 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 3-15 thru 4-14 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 4-15 thru 6-14 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 6-15 thru 8-14 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 8-15 thru 10-14 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 10-15 thru 12-14 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 12-15 thru 13-14 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 13-15 thru 14-14 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 14-15 thru 15-14 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 15-15 thru 16-29 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 16-30 thru 17-41 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 1-50, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 51-100, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 101-150, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 151-200, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 201-250, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 251-300, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 301-350, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 351-400, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 401-450, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 451-500, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - The War Between the Tates - pp. 501-555, setting copy (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Franco-Erican War - used and cut (A),The War Between the Tates (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Franco-Erican War - used and cut (B), The War Between the Tates (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Franco-Erican War - used and cut (C), The War Between the Tates (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - War Novel - Reviews and Letters - Eng., 1974-06-1975-05 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - War Novel - U.S. Letters, 1974-1975, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - War - Reviews - America, 1974-05-1975-01 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      Book cover with reviews
  - Counting Sheep
    - Counting Sheep - early versions and notes (A) (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Counting Sheep - early versions and notes (B) (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Counting Sheep - early versions and notes (C) (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Women and Ghosts
    - Women and Ghosts - "Ilse's House" (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Women and Ghosts - "The Pool People" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Women and Ghosts - "The Highboy" (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Women and Ghosts - "Counting Sheep" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Women and Ghosts - "In the Shadow" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Women and Ghosts - "Waiting for the Baby" (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Women and Ghosts - "Fat People" (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Women and Ghosts - "Another Halloween" (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Women and Ghosts - "The Double Poet" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Women and Ghosts - Revisions: "Ilse's House" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Women and Ghosts - Notes/drafts: "The Pool People" (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Women and Ghosts - Notes/drafts: "The Highboy" (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Women and Ghosts - Notes/drafts: "Counting Sheep" (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Women and Ghosts - Notes/drafts: "In the Shadow" and "Another Halloween" (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Women and Ghosts - Notes/drafts: "The Double Poet" (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Women and Ghosts - style sheet, text page make-up sheet, composition specs, manuscript, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Ghosts - NY, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Women + Ghosts - London, 1989-1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, articles
    - Women + Ghosts - Reprints, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Ghosts - London - Reviews, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Last Resort
    - The Last Resort - character, plans, chronology, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The Last Resort - epigraphs and research, 1994-5 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - The Last Resort - notes, 1995-6 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - The Last Resort - used notes, 1995-7 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Last Resort - early chapters (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Last Resort - notes, 1995-6 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Last Resort - notes, used and cut, 1995-6 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Last Resort - notes, used and cut, ch. 1-2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Last Resort - notes, used and cut, ch. 3-5 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - The Last Resort - notes, used and cut, ch. 6-8 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - The Last Resort - notes, used and cut, ch. 9-11 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - The Last Resort - manuscript 1-1 to 3-20 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Last Resort - manuscript 4-1 to 6-21 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Last Resort - manuscript 7-1 to 9-25 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Last Resort - manuscript 10-1 to 11-24 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Last Resort - manuscript 12-1 to 15-25 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - The Last Resort - typescript 1-7 to 12-11a (corrections) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - The Last Resort - typescript Manatees, 1-1 to 3-22 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Last Resort - typescript 4-1 to 6-21 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Last Resort - typescript 7-1 to 9-28 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Last Resort - typescript 10-1 to 12-22 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Last Resort - typescript 13-1 to 15-27 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - The Last Resort - notes used and cut (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Last Resort - Letters, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      Includes a book cover
    - Last Resort - NY - Reviews, Letters, 1998-04-1998-09 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Last Resort - London, Letters + Reviews, 1998-04-1999-02 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Last Resort - England, 1997-04-1999-03 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      Photo of Ann Beattis; two book covers; Cornell correspondence
  - The Nowhere City
    - The Nowhere City - British edition: reviews, letters, 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Nowhere City - US edition, 1963-67 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Nowhere City - US edition: letters and reviews, 1965-74 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Nowhere City - France, 1965-67 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - The Nowhere City - England, 1964-76 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Nowhere City - Letters, 1962-06-1966-04 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Series II. Other Works
  - Reflections of a Lady Writer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yaddo - Notes - General (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yaddo - Used and cut first draft (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yaddo - Used and cut second draft (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Pool People, 12 Jan 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Rabbit - Notes and drafts, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ilse's House - short story in New York Woman, Apr 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Familiar Spirits (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Familiar Spirits - manuscript annotated by Sandy McClatchy (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Only Children - Notes (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Waiting for the Baby - Notes and revisions, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Saturday's Brides - Mademoiselle article, April 1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Truth and Consequences - notes (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Truth and Consequences - used and cut (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
  - Real People - annotated first chapter by Roth (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Polly - Reviews, Letters, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Related to The Truth About Lorin Jones; includes early notes for Lorin Jones
  - Polly - US, 1988-1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    Project description with tentative title
  - Polly - London, 1987-05-1988-08 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Book Cover
  - Language of Clothes, London Reviews Letters, 1982-1985 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Language of Clothes, reprint London, 1988-1992, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Language of Clothes, Reviews + Letters US, 1981-1985 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Oxford/Fairy Tales - London, 1990-10-1993-12 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Book cover
  - Oxford - Fairy Tales - NY, 1991-11-1993-10 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Fairy Tales: Not used in book, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Only Children, Reviews London, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Only Children - London, 1978-07-1979-08 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Only Children - US Reviews, 1979-03-1979-10 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Undated American Library Association Booklist
  - Only Children - US, 1978-01-1985-10 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Copy of book cover, actual book cover
  - Only Children - Letters, Apr 1979 - Nov 1979, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Yaddo - RP - Reviews e Letters, 1969, 1972, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Related to Real People
  - Yaddo England - Reviews e Letters, 1970, 1973, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Reviews for The Nowhere City, Imaginary Friends, Real People
  - Yado - England, 1968-06-1970-08 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Book cover for Real People
  - Yaddo - USA, 1968-04-1969-09 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Comments on Real People
  - Truth + Consequences - Reviews, 2005-09-2006-02 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Book covers; undated copies
  - Truth + Consequences - Reviews, 2004-09-2005-10 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Don't Tell - US, 1984-12-1990-06 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Don't Tell - US - Reviews, Letters, 1990-01-1990-10 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Undated cards, undated fan letter
  - Don't Tell - England, 1989-03-1991-08 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Book covers
  - Don't Tell - England - Reviews, 1990-05-1990-06 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Boys + Girls Forever, 1992-2005 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Pamphlet for "The Oz Centennial" 1900-2000; copy of an excerpt; pamphlet for Finnish creator of Moomin; book covers
  - Sheep, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Original folder labeled as "Never Published"; includes illustrations
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Letters from writers (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Letters from writers: Sue Kaufman, Christopher Isherwood, Olivia Manning, Arthur Mizener, Jean Stafford, Edmund Wilson (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Saul Bellow letter, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Robert Creely e-mail (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Robert Creely letters (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Edward Gorey, 1952-1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Imaginary Friends, correspondence and clippings 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Imaginary Friends TV, correspondence and clippings 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Howard Nemerov 1968 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Letters from Anthony and Violet Powell, 1964-2001 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Letters from Philip Roth, 1964-2013 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Emmy - Letters From Friends, 1961-1962, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - Spiritualist Hymnal, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette: Alison Lurie, V-846 [production cassette] 1985 (Box 13)
  - Videocassette: Foreign Affair, Part 1, V-847 [VHS] 1992 (Box 13)
  - Videocassette: Imaginary Friends, Part 3, V-848 [VHS] (Box 13)
  - Audiocassette: Ithaca College Reading, tr8167a 1985 (Box 13)
  - Audiocassette: Reading from Only Children, tr8168a (Box 13)
  - Audiocassette: Interview, tr8169a (Box 13)
  - Audiocassette: Listening and Reading 3, sides 1 and 2, tr8170a 1990 (Box 13)
  - Audiocassette: Listening and Reading 3, sides 3 and 4, tr8171a 1990 (Box 13)
  - Interviews, 1987-1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Seminar notes 1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)